<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on jwhogg</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on jwhogg</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Budgeting App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio3/</guid>
      <description>Github 🔗&#xA;On ongoing project of mine, taking inspriation from Monzo&amp;rsquo;s budgeting burndown feature. I&amp;rsquo;m building this web app with Ruby-on-Rails, and using the GoCardless API to handle linking user&amp;rsquo;s bank accounts to the app securely.&#xA;So far, I am building the MVP, and have implemented functionality to link a bank account with the app, and to store the user&amp;rsquo;s key to access their bank account data using server-side sessions, which are much more secure than cookies sesion storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal Implicit GAN: Data Augmentation for Causal Discovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio2/</guid>
      <description>Github 🔗&#xA;My University dissertation research project, where I designed and trained a GAN model for data augmentation (generating new training samples for downstream models). I was very proud to receive a score of 83 on this disseration (high 1st).&#xA;The data the GAN generates is intended for use on Causal Discovery models, an area where quality ground-truth datasets are hard to come by- making data augmentation a valuable technique. The novel contribution of my project is that the GAN is designed to implicitly learn causal relations, which we hypothesise leads to more &amp;lsquo;realistic&amp;rsquo; output data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning GPT2-2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio4/</guid>
      <description>Github 🔗&#xA;A brief jupyter notebook I made showing how to fine tune a model using the 🤗 Transformers libary. The example I wrote uses the popular CNN/DailyMail dataset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Youtube2Summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio1/</guid>
      <description>Github 🔗&#xA;🤗 Pipeline to generate summaries of youtube videos, using Whisper-Small for transcription, and BART-LARGE-XSUM for summarisation.&#xA;BART has been finetuned on the popular CNN/Daily Mail Dataset, as it lends itself to summarisation tasks. Initially, we attempted to fine-tune GPT-2 for the summarisation task, but found it had poor performance: being a generative transfotmer, it generates words one-by-one, (extractive summarisation) whereas BART can generate at the sentence level (using abstractive summarisation).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
